<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Featured publications on Alexis Rivera</title>
    <link>https://alexis-ribal.github.io/portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Featured publications on Alexis Rivera</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; 2020 a hugo theme by somrat</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 12:14:34 +0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://alexis-ribal.github.io/portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Nonrenewable wealth</title>
      <link>https://alexis-ribal.github.io/portfolio/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 12:14:34 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alexis-ribal.github.io/portfolio/project-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chapter 9 in the Changing Wealth of Nations 2021 report that explores countries&amp;rsquo; nonrenewable natural wealth (oil, gas, coal and minerals).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This chapter describes the economic importance of nonrenewable natural wealth in all countries using the data from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.worldbank.org/cwon&#34;&gt;www.worldbank.org/cwon&lt;/a&gt; and discusses the main risks that countries face when they have abundance of these nonrenewable natural resources.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some of the main messages of this chapter include: nonrenewable assets are important for the economy, however, overreliance on them could be risky.  This chapter recommends government officials and policymakers to acknowledge these risks and diversify their economies to avoid shocks that can harm their economies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wealth accounting</title>
      <link>https://alexis-ribal.github.io/portfolio/project-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 12:14:34 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alexis-ribal.github.io/portfolio/project-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chapter 11 in the Changing Wealth of Nations 2021 report that discusses how wealth accounting (natural, human and physical capital) can be used to design sustainable macroeconomic and fiscal policies.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This chapter combines data from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.worldbank.org/cwon&#34;&gt;www.worldbank.org/cwon&lt;/a&gt; with other public accounts and datasets while comparing different groups of countries to assess economic and fiscal performance over 20 years of data.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The figures and analysis show that policymakers can complement traditional economic analysis with wealth components to unveil long term challenges that can undermine public finance resilience to shocks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Giant oil fields</title>
      <link>https://alexis-ribal.github.io/portfolio/project-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 12:14:34 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alexis-ribal.github.io/portfolio/project-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This database is part of an article published in the American Association of Petroleum Geologists Memoir 125 &amp;ldquo;Giant Fields of the Decade: 2010-2020&amp;rdquo; edited by C. A. Sternbach, R. K. Merrill, and J. C. Dolson.  We extended the giant oil field discoveries between 1868 and 2010 recorded by Horn and Halbouty to 2019 and calculated the economic magnitude of them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This dataset is helping ongoing research on the economic and institutional performance of resource-rich countries to assess the impact of these major economic shocks and the risks that imply.  Some of the research articles and working papers can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://resources4transformation.org/publications/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Project Title</title>
      <link>https://alexis-ribal.github.io/portfolio/project-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 12:14:34 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alexis-ribal.github.io/portfolio/project-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Este artículo es parte del número 137 de la revista Brújula Ciudadana editada por el equipo de Iniciativa Ciudadana para la Promoción de la Cultura del Diálogo A.C.  El artículo analiza las consecuencias del conflicto entre Ucrania y Rusia en los mercados internacionales de commodities y cómo éstos pueden impactar las economías de América Latina.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Este texto sugiere que ante una eventual escalada del conflicto y de las sanciones económicas por parte de países occidentales, los precios de algunos commodities podrían sufrir un boom que crearía ganadores y perdedores en las economías latinoamericanas.  Por lo tanto, los diseñadores de políticas públicas deberían poner atención en los cambios de estos mercados para mitigar los riesgos que pudieran surgir.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tree mapping</title>
      <link>https://alexis-ribal.github.io/portfolio/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 12:14:34 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alexis-ribal.github.io/portfolio/project-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is an article published in the Development Engineering Journal of UC Berkeley that present the results of a part of a World Bank project that aims to evaluate the effectiveness of payment for ecosystem services in the Sahel semi-arid forests.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This article proposes a methodology to map tree cover in gazetted forests of Burkina Faso using open access multispectral satellite imagery and Google Earth Engine platform.  This methodology could be used to measure changes in tree cover over a period in areas with sparse vegetation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ecosystem Assessment</title>
      <link>https://alexis-ribal.github.io/portfolio/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 12:14:34 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alexis-ribal.github.io/portfolio/project-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is an article coauthored with Dr. Jen Burney and Dr. Ran Godlblatt at the UC San Diego&amp;rsquo;s School of Global Policy and Strategy and UC San Diego&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://bigpixel.ucsd.edu/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Big Pixel Initiative&lt;/a&gt;.  We used high 3-band and medium multi-spectral resolution satellite images to map tree cover in the Brazilian Sertāo.  We used random forest-based supervised machine learning to determine the classification accuracy of this method and compared the results with both types of images.  The results show that using high-resolution imagery with only RGB bands yields better results than medium-resolution imagery with 11 bands such as Landsat 8.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Relaciones subnacionales</title>
      <link>https://alexis-ribal.github.io/portfolio/project-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 12:14:34 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alexis-ribal.github.io/portfolio/project-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(In Spanish) Este documento de trabajo publicado en la División de Estudios Internacionales en coautoría con el Dr. Carlos Heredia Zubieta dentro del Centro de Investigación y Docencia Económicas (CIDE) recopila y analiza los vínculos que han establecido los gobiernos subnacionales de México con los de China, fortaleciendo en México lo que se conoce como la «paradiplomacia».&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Esta investigación busca resaltar el papel de los municipios y estados en la construcción de relaciones internacionales entre los dos países y propone una serie de acciones que permitan el fortalecimiento del diálogo entre autoridades gubernamentales y así detonar una mayor interacción económica, política, educativa, cultural y científica.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
