<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Geospatial on Alexis Rivera</title>
    <link>https://alexis-ribal.github.io/es/categories/geospatial/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Geospatial on Alexis Rivera</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>es-es</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; 2020 a hugo theme by somrat</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 12:14:34 +0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://alexis-ribal.github.io/es/categories/geospatial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tree mapping</title>
      <link>https://alexis-ribal.github.io/es/portfolio/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 12:14:34 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alexis-ribal.github.io/es/portfolio/project-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is an article published in the Development Engineering Journal of UC Berkeley that present the results of a part of a World Bank project that aims to evaluate the effectiveness of payment for ecosystem services in the Sahel semi-arid forests.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This article proposes a methodology to map tree cover in gazetted forests of Burkina Faso using open access multispectral satellite imagery and Google Earth Engine platform.  This methodology could be used to measure changes in tree cover over a period in areas with sparse vegetation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ecosystem Assessment</title>
      <link>https://alexis-ribal.github.io/es/portfolio/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 12:14:34 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alexis-ribal.github.io/es/portfolio/project-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is an article coauthored with Dr. Jen Burney and Dr. Ran Godlblatt at the UC San Diego&amp;rsquo;s School of Global Policy and Strategy and UC San Diego&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://bigpixel.ucsd.edu/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Big Pixel Initiative&lt;/a&gt;.  We used high 3-band and medium multi-spectral resolution satellite images to map tree cover in the Brazilian Sertāo.  We used random forest-based supervised machine learning to determine the classification accuracy of this method and compared the results with both types of images.  The results show that using high-resolution imagery with only RGB bands yields better results than medium-resolution imagery with 11 bands such as Landsat 8.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
